Mike!
麦克!
Did you sweep the pool?
游泳池你清了没?
Why? Because people wanna swim.
怎了? 因为有人要游泳啊!
How are you feeling today, ma? Feeling great, Mike. Good.
妈! 今天觉得如何? 神清气爽, 麦克 很好
Where's dad? Crossword.
老爸勒? 在玩字谜(大便时的娱乐)
Checking out of 202. How was your stay, Mr Edmunds?
202退房 住得怎样啊? 艾德曼先生
Fine, thanks. Thank you so much.
不错! 谢谢 非常感谢您
So two nights, preferably upstairs. Oh sure.
住两晚, 最好是2楼上面的 喔! 当然
Let's see, smoking or non smoking? Non smoking.
我来看看..抽不抽烟? 不抽烟的
I got you into 203. Okay.
我帮你安排203房 好的
Nice room. Oh this is our snack bar, the prices are on the wall.
很棒的房间，喔!这是我们的小吃部 价格都写在墙上
Sorry.
拍谢
There you go. Thank you.
这给你 谢谢
Anything else you should need, just give me a call. Thank you very much.
有任何需要，尽管打电话过来 多谢罗
Do you need help with your bags? No, I'm fine.
行李需要帮忙吗? 不了，我自己来就好
110's called twice to complain that 111's making too much noise.
110房打来两次电话 抱怨说111房太吵杂了
Yeah, what kind of noise? Not that kind of noise Mike, now get your mind out of the gutter.
喔,是哪种吵杂声?
Apparently 111's got some sort of grinder in there.
显然是111房客带了什么磨豆机 进来
I thought you said to get my mind out of the gutter? Don't be gross, Mike.
我以为你说的是我想的那种低级 别那么恶，麦克
Get some sleep, you look tired. I'm not tired.
去睡个觉，你看来累了 我不累
You look tired. You're the one who's sick, ma.
你是累了 你才是那个会累坏的人，妈!
Now that's a nice thing to say.
总算说话还点有良心
Sorry. I love you.
谢谢啦.. 我爱你
Love you too. Good night, dad. All right.
老妈也爱你 老爸 晚安罗! 走罗!
Who is it? Management.
谁啊? 客服
What? Management. Welcome gift.
啥? 旅馆客服，送来欢迎的礼物
Hi. Hi.
嗨! 嗨!
I have your complimentary bottle...welcome gift.
我给你送来免费的..欢迎礼物
Wine. It's on the house.
一瓶酒 专为这间房送的
I'm uh, oh, Mike. And I am with management.
我叫..呃..麦克 这里是我经营的
Nice to meet you, Mike. Oh it's...uh...my pleasure.
高兴认识你 麦克 喔! 真是..呃..我的荣幸!
So, where would you like it? You know what I can just, I can just take it.
那么，你要放哪里? 你知道我可以..我拿就好了
Oh, okay.
喔! 好的
Do you uh, I'm sorry. Would you like me to open it? For you?
不好意思...呃 你介意我帮你打开吗?
I mean. Yeah, cause sometimes guests don't have screws. Or, screws.
我是说..因为有时客人没有开瓶器 或是不会开..
Yeah, okay, sure.
对厚..好吧
Just close this here.
这先关起来
Thanks.
谢谢
Anything interesting tonight?
今晚有什么好看的吗?
I haven't really been paying attention.
我没有很注意看
I know the feeling.
我知道那感觉(独处)
You know, there should be cups in the bathroom.
知道吧，浴室应该有杯子
Completely sanitary. That's good.
完全卫生的 很好啊
Wine is delicious.
酒很香醇
Shall I?
可以吗?
Okay, sure.
好啦, 倒吧
Pretty good year.
很棒的年份
Sometimes guests like me to join in and have a taste.
有时候客人喜欢我加入一起品尝
Is that right? Not always but...often.
真的? 不是常有的啦...偶而
Should be another cup in the bathroom. I should get to work Mike, so...
浴室里应该有其他的杯子 我该工作了， 麦克， 所以..
What do you do? I sell paintings.
你做什么的? 我卖画的
Really? I love paintings. What kind?
是喔! 我爱死画作了 是哪种画?
That kind.
那一种
Oooooh. Nice. So that's what you're doing in town.
喔..喔 漂亮! 那么这就是你来这小镇的目的?
I give presentations tomorrow and then I fly out the next morning.
我明天有个展览会 后天早上我就搭机离开这里
What say...the company that you work for? It's called Corporate Bliss.
如此说来..你在哪家公司上班? 叫做 比利斯集团
And where you guys HQ? Maryland.
那么你们总部在哪里? 马里兰州
Nice. Wait! 'Maryland, is for lovers'.
很棒啊 等等! 马里兰是恋爱之乡耶
It's Virginia, actually 'Virginia is for lovers'.
那是维吉尼亚 事实上维吉尼亚才是恋爱之乡
'Maryland is for crabs'. Yeah, you're right.
马里兰是螃蟹之乡 对! 你说的对!
Okay Mike... Okay, I gotta get back to work. Oh, solitary, great game.
好了，麦克.. 好了我得回去工作 喔! 接龙喔，好游戏
Okay, I'm gonna be down in the lobby till 11, then in my apartment after that.
我会下楼在大厅待到11点 然后会回去我的住所
But I can always be reached by a front door buzzer.
不过我随时带着门房呼叫器
From then on. Just take it easy on your solitary problem.
那样你就不用担心独处的问题
Yeah, have a great night. Good night!
那么..晚安罗 好...好..掰掰!
...laundry room and then I came down here into the lobby,
..从洗衣间然后进来这接待厅
and that's when I realized that your establishment doesn't have any options for recycling.
这时我才知道你们旅馆 没有任何资源回收措施
You're absolutely right, we don't. Which I apologize for.
你说的很对，我们是没有 我为此致歉
It's something we're working on.
那是我们正在努力改进的工作
But as you may know the Kingman area has been a little slow to fully embrace the recycling issue.
但你应该知道，在金曼这地方要推动资源再生法条是很缓慢的
It's been voted on to... What should I do with this bottle?
这议题还得靠投票表决... 那这瓶子我该如何处理?
Well... I'm sorry, I don't mean to be rude,
嗯... 抱歉，我无意失礼
but this is something that I'm just, I'm very passionate about.
但我对某些事情有强烈的关注
Recycling? Yes, recycling.
资源回收? 对! 资源回收
Let me take it. I'll do it.
给我吧! 我来做
I was gonna make a recycling round anyway.
我无时无刻都在做资源回收工作
Well, that's nice of you.
对嘛! 你人真好
This is my son Michael, he is the official night manager.
这是我儿子 麦克 他是经营夜班的
Thank you. It's very nice of you.
谢谢 你人非常好
You bet. I'll just be out the back here with all my other ones.
打个赌 待会出来会把我所有回收物都带出来
I got a pretty good, big pile...
我搜集一大堆...
Who is it? Mike.
谁啊? 麦克
Oh god.
喔! 天啊!
Champagne. Why?
香槟 为何?
We give it to all our guests who stay for two nights.
我们为所有住房两晚的客人提供的
Wow, that's a pretty good deal.
哇! 这实在是很划算
Did you and your mom come up with that on your own?
你和你妈都这样为客人服务吗?
So shall I?
那么我可以?...
Why not?
有何不可?
Réserve. You know, they're always at the same place. The cups.
典藏的..杯子都在同一个地方 你知道的..
Thank you.
多谢
Do you make a toast, Mike? Hm, yeah, sure.
要来个祝酒辞吗? 麦克 嗯.. 好啊..当然要
You're Sue, right? Yeah.
你叫 苏, 对吧? 是
Here's to...people being happy!
以此仅祝...所有人都快乐!
How were your presentations today?
你今天的展览办得如何?
Average.
普普而已
You have a great butt.
你的屁股很漂亮
I noticed the moment you checked in and...
你在办进住时我注意到了 而且...
Thank you.
多谢
Hope that isn't too, you know... No. I mean yeah, but...
希望这次不像以前一样.. 不! 我意思是.. 但...
Do you do this a lot, Mike? No.
你常用这招吗? 麦克 没
Sometimes? Fairly rarely.
有时? 简直少到没有
Does it ever work? Never.
有成功过吗? 从来没有
What would constitute having it work?
要怎样才算成功?
Us having sex?
我们上床?..
You getting to touch my butt?
让你摸到我的屁股?..
That would... Yeah, I'd consider that...fairly...constitution...
那是... 对! 我认为那样..就是..成功的章程
Okay.
好吧
You can touch my butt but then you gotta go.
你可以摸我屁股 然后你就走人
Okay. Are you serious?
来啊 你不是开玩笑吧?
Yeah, touch it and go, Mike! Just touch and go.
对啊! 摸了就滚，麦克 摸了就滚
You're sure from Maryland? Yeah.
你真的来自马里兰? 对
Where about? Columbia. What about you?
那里民风如何? 像哥伦比亚，那你呢?
Here. Kingman.
这地方的傻不愣登 金曼小镇
It's very warm.
好温暖..
Okay, Mike. I got an early plane to catch and well... Yeah, me too.
好罗!麦克 我得赶早班飞机 是啊! 我也该滚了
Bye bye now. Bye.
掰掰罗! 掰!
Mom? Hi, it's me. I'm just checking in. I'm in Kingman, Arizona.
妈?是我啦 我在亚利桑那金曼镇 刚办好入住登记
Okay, that's it. I love you and I miss you. Okay.
好啦! 就这样 我爱你也想你喔! 搞定!
Hi Sue. Hi.
嗨! 苏 嗨
I was wondering if I could snag your cellphone number or your email before you left?
我在想在你离开前是否可以要个 手机号码或E MAIL的?
I don't think so, Mike. Why not?
我想没办法，麦克 怎么不行?
Ah...not my style.
呃...这不是我的作风
But...we...you know, I uh, touched your butt.
但..我们..你知道的啊 我..呃..摸了你屁股
I know. And it was nice.
我知道，而且感觉也不错
I just think that's all she wrote.
我只是认为 那都是她(我)主导的
That was...
我想...
Mike, are those high boots? Yeah. You're not gonna get these off.
麦克，那是长筒鞋吧? 对啊! 那就不要脱了
You're all checked out? Yeah, I get it with your wife. Earlier.
你退房了? 是啊! 稍早我向你太太办的
Hey, dad. Oh! Come back and see us some time.
嘿! 爸! 喔! 有空要回来看我们!
Mhm, yah, now you know it all depends on work.
嗯嗯..会的 现在你知道都是为了工作了吧!?
What was that all about? She sells motel paintings.
你们在搞啥飞机? 她是卖旅馆挂画的
Mike, the heat's out in 118.
麦克，118房空调坏罗!
Thank you for calling Last Minute Flights. I'd like to book a... Your call is important to us... Fuck!
感谢您拨打廉价航空订位专线
Please continue to hold. Your call will be answered in an orderly fashion...
请保持通话 您的电话将由值班专员接听..
Okay Mike, now or never.
好! 麦克! 不要丧失良机!
I'm gonna do it! Hello, Last Minute Flights, how may I assist you?
我要干下去! 哈罗!廉价航空，有何需要服务的?
Hi! Yeah! I'd like to book a one way cash ticket
嗨! 对! 我要订一张
for as fast as possible from Phoenix to Baltimore. Got it?
从凤凰城到巴尔的摩最快的单程票! 了解吗?
Hi, I'm here to see Sue Claussen. Is she expecting you?
嗨! 我来找 苏 克劳森 她在等你吗?
Um yeah, I've left a couple of messages. Messages regarding...?
嗯..对! 我得留个口讯 关于什么的口讯..?
Regarding Sue, telling her I was in town. I'm an old friend.
关于 苏，跟她说我是乡下来的 一个老朋友
I see.
了解了
Sue, hi!
苏! 嗨!
What are you doing here? I was wondering if we could talk.
你来这里做什么? 我在想我们是否可以谈一下
Why are you here? I called twice, did you get the messages?
你为何来这里? 我打了两次电话 你你有收到留言吗?
You know what guys, I'm sorry, why don't you go ahead.
你们认识这家伙吗? 不好意思! 你们何不先过去?
Are you sure, Sue? Yes, good, go.
没问题吗? 苏 对! 很好，去吧!
Good.
很好!
Can I talk to you for a second?
能过来说几句吗? 好啊!
This is completely inappropriate.
这实在是完全不恰当的!
This is like a violation.
呃..嗯.. 这像是一种骚扰!
I wasn't trying to violate... Yes you did.
我不是想要来骚扰... 对! 你已经做了!
You are. You're violating my personal space, you're violating my personal life.
你就是! 你正骚扰我的私人空间 你正骚扰我的私人生活!
I can't do this, I have to be somewhere, I'm late.
我不能如此瞎耗 我得去个地方，要迟到了
It's five o'clock what can you be late for?
现在5点了耶! 还有什么可迟到的?
I have an event.
我有个比赛活动
You have an event? What kind of an event?
你有个比赛活动? 哪种活动啊?
I can't tell you.
我不告诉你
Can I come?
我可以跟吗?
Here. Come on you need it.
这个 来啦! 你需要喝下
You do this every week? Yeah.
你每个礼拜都玩这个? 对!
You're really good at it.
你实在很厉害
You can't stay, Mike. Why not?
你不可以待在这边，麦克 有何不可了?
Cause it's insane.
因为这实在太不正常了
I let you touch my butt and then you fly halfway across the country.
我让你抓下屁股 然后你就飞过半个国家跑来?!
Well it was much more than a butt touch.
嗯.. 这比抓个屁股更有意义啊!
Still you can't stay. I've got a lot of work to do.
反正你不能留在这边 我有很多工作要做
Well how much stuff can you do in one night? A lot.
那么你一个晚上有多少事情要做? 很多!
Like what? You got out with friends or...?
比如说勒..? 你和朋友一起出门或者..
You see that girl over there?
有没看到那边那个女的?
She works for Burger King. She gives me vouchers every week.
她在汉堡王工作 每个礼拜会给我一些餐券
And I pass them out.
而我就故意放她们水
That's what I do.
那就是我在做的工作
I just wanna let you know. If you want me to leave tomorrow, I will, I promise.
我只是想让你知道 如果你要我明天离开，我会的，我保证
Hey guys! Sue is here.
嘿! 大伙儿! 苏 来了
Whopper. Whopper. Whopper. Whopper. Whopper.
特大号 特大号 特大号 特大号...
Okay, Chicken Tenders.
好罗! 换香嫩火鸡餐
Here you go, Chicken Tender.
给你的，香嫩火鸡餐
Ok. BK veggie burger.
好罗! 汉堡王蔬菜堡 呃....
Not that, Sue. Come on, it's supposed to be delicious.
不要那个啦! 苏 别这样啦! 把它想成很好吃的样子
I don't think so... Come on guys, it's got soya in it, it's good, it's really good.
我不这么认为..
Fine, I'll take one.
好! 我拿一份
All right, hey, who wants a powerade? All right.
好了，嘿.. 有谁要“劲力饮料”?..很好
This is nice. Thanks. I've been here two years.
很漂亮哇! 多谢! 我住两年了
Compact fluorescents. Oh. Bummer.
小型萤光灯 喔! 好失望(死白目乡巴佬)
So I think I'm gonna, go to sleep.
那么我想我要去睡了
You want me to touch your butt first?
你要我先抓下你屁股吗?
No. I only do that when I'm travelling.
不! 我只在旅游时才会那样做
Right.
好吧
So do you...are you alone here in Maryland
那么..你独自一人在马里兰..
or do you have relatives around or...? My mom, she's over in Laurel. That...
还是有其他亲属在附近..?
Her name is Mary. What does she do?
她叫 玛莉 她做什么的?
She sells insurance to deaf people.
她卖听障保险的
Nice sweatsuit.
漂亮的运动服
I don't want you to take this the wrong way
我不希望你动歪脑筋
but I think we probably shouldn't sleep in the same bed.
我认为我们不该睡同一张床
It's a good call.
正确的决定!
So is your return ticket all set?
那么你回程票都处理好了?
I actually don't have one. You don't have a return ticket?
事实上我没有 你没有回程机票?
I bought a one way. Why?
我买一张单程票 怎会这样?
That's completely unacceptable, Mike. I know.
那实在让人难以理解耶! 麦克 我知道
You need to buy one. I know, I'm sorry. I didn't have enough money.
你应该买一张啊! 我知道，很抱歉!我没多的钱..
What? I only had enough for a one way.
啥? 我的钱只够买张单程的
And I thought, I thought, I'm just gonna go for it. With me?
而我想..我想..就直接做下去 因为我?
Yes. It was a far flung notion. That was a fucking stupid notion.
对! 这是个远见的打算 那是个她妈的白痴打算!
I guess. I'll lend you the money.
我是这么认为 我会借钱给你
No, you don't have to do that! Yeah, well I'm going to.
别啦! 你不需要那么做! 对! 我正要做
Okay, hey, would you first consider taking a morning off from work?
好啦! 嘿! 你不想在上班前先来个晨间活动?
No. We can hang out and then I'll leave.
不要! 我们可以小玩一下然后我就走人
If I don't you can...mace me.
如果我食言.. 你大可槌死我
You're insane. We could go to the zoo, that'd be fun.
你有毛病 我们可以逛逛动物园，应该不错玩
Mike, zoos suck. Okay, then we'll do something else.
麦克, 动物园很逊耶! 好好, 那么我们做其他的事
Come on Sue, take a day off from work, you look like you could use it.
好啦! 苏，就请一天假 你看来似乎该请假
I do?
我有必要吗?
Have me buzz those people, come on, let me take it!
让我来搞那些人 快啦! 让我来开!
Not too hard okay?
别那么猛，好吗?
You shouldn't smoke.
你不该抽烟的
I'm done. Forever. I'm serious.
我戒了，永远戒 我说真的
No, you don't...hey! You don't need to do that.
不! 你不要... 嘿! 你无需那么做
Yeah but I am, I'm done.
是不需要啊! 但我戒了
It's time.
是时候要戒了
Let's see if I understand something. Do you think that you like me, Mike?
来说说就我假设的事 你认为你喜欢我? 麦克
Yes. Why?
对的! 怎会勒?
Cause you have style.
因为你有个性
No I don't. Yeah you do.
不! 我没有 有就是有
No, no. I don't. Yeah.
不!不!没有 有啦
You give away 30% of your income.
你捐赠出自己30%的收入做慈善
You would to if you'd...make...more. No I wouldn't.
如果你赚更多..你也会.. 不!我才不会
You're also incredibly sweet.
同时你又这么甜美
Well beneath... Beneath what?
有点可惜... 可惜什么?
Beneath the part of you that's not.
可惜你那性观念部分
I'm gonna get you bus.
我要送你上巴士了
I'll pay you back for the ticket. Don't worry about it.
我会还你票钱的 别在意那个
So will I ever see you again?
那么我还可以见到你吗?
That wouldn't be good for you, Mike. I'm not good with people.
那对你不大好，麦克 我不善与别人相处
No, that's not true. Yeah, I know it is.
不! 那不是事实 对! 我心知肚明
No, it's not. What about those homeless guys? They love you.
不! 不是那样 那些街友怎样? 他们都爱你啊
What about the soccer gals?
那些足球女郎如何?
What about me?
那我勒?
Okay, buddy, all aboard.
好罗, 老兄, 都上车罗
Hey, Mike, I think you better go on the bus.
嘿，麦克 我觉得你该上车了
Hey Sue, it's Mike. Calling, again, I'm trying not to call too much but,
嘿!苏! 我是麦克，我又打来了 我尽量不要打太多电话，
I just wanted to make sure that you got the poem that I sent last week
但我只是想确认一下 你有没收到我上星期寄给你的诗
you know, the sort of an elongated haiku thing...
知道吗? 就是那种很长的俳句那种东西..
But seriously, you should call cause I'm definitely around.
说实在的， 我一厢情愿认为你会打电话过来
Anyway, talk to you later, I hope, bye.
无论如何，我希望再跟你说话 掰...
I thought you were gonna quit smoking?
我以为你早戒烟了?
I just did.
我刚戒掉...
What are you doing here?
来这里做啥啊?
Work.
工作
Hey, did you, did you get my haiku? The elongated one?
嘿!你有..你有收到我的俳句吗? 又臭又长那个?
Yeah. Yeah.
对啊 有啦!
It was nice.
写的很美
So you're just uh, passing through?
那么你只是..呃 路过而已?
Yeah, fly out from Phoenix tomorrow.
是啊! 明天就飞离凤凰城
Here, I'll take it. Oh, thank you.
来，给我拿 喔! 谢谢
So, this must be a really good region for corporate art sales?
那么，这次一定是很好的卖艺区域?
Yes, it is.
对! 没错
Hey, I'm supposed to go to this yoga class later.
嘿! 待会我想去上瑜珈课
Would you like to come with me?
你要不要跟我一起去?
Do you have a boyfriend Sue? No.
你有男朋友吗? 苏 没有
Did you, recently? Yes.
是吗? 最近的 有
What was his name? Jango.
叫啥名字? 强哥
He was an ex punk. Ex, like ex punk?
他是个庞克乐手 乐手, 像是庞克艺人?
Ex rock punk.
摇滚庞克演奏手
We broke up when he moved away.
他搬走后我们就分手了
Why did he leave?
他为何离开?
To open the Pacific northwest branch of his organic yoghurt company.
去西北太平洋区张罗有关他的 奶酪分公司
He's the president. Here you go.
他是总裁 您点的菜来了
Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
多谢
So how is your job these days? It's okay.
那么你这些日子工作如何? 还好啦!
But it's not your fantasy job. I don't really do fantasy about it.
那不是你梦幻的工作 我没当它是梦幻的工作
If you could close your eyes and pick anything what would it be?
如果你闭上眼睛然后随便抓个东西看会变成怎样?
But you gotta close your eyes otherwise it's not gonna work.
但你得闭上眼睛 否则就不灵了
Okay.
好吧
To run a full service state of the art soup kitchen.
经营一家隆重服务的精致汤品餐厨
Multiple housing units upstairs, recreational facilities in the basement,
有多样的高级家饰 地下室有许多娱乐设施
job outreach.
业务扩展..
Midnight basketball.
..午夜篮球...
Good soup. Excellent soup, first and foremost.
好汤 很赞的汤,最好最有名的
What about kids, you wanna have kids?
小孩勒? 有想过生个小孩吗?
You know what was really great about that yoga class?
你知道瑜珈课真正棒的地方在哪吗?
It was the breathing stuff.
那是关于呼吸调节的玩意儿
I don't do that. Breathe?
我是不做那个的 呼吸?
There are days where I have to instruct my heart to request additional air.
曾几何时我必须命令我的心脏 要接纳额外的空气
And I have to tell myself: 'Breathe, Sue'.
然后我告诉自己: “呼吸..苏”
'Just keep breathing'.
“继续保持呼吸”...
Yes, I want kids.
对! 我想要小孩
Were you not sure when I asked?
我这样问你不会觉得奇怪吗?
I just don't think that I've ever been asked. That way. Before.
我只想从来没被这样问过.. 那种事情...以前从未
Can I ask one more question? Then I'm done, I swear.
可以再问个问题吗? 然后我就此打住，我发誓
Will you come visit my mom with me on the way home?
在回家路上你可以随我去看我妈吗?
She's sick and I um, I promised I'd stop by.
她生病了而我...嗯.. 答应顺便过去看看
Here, these are for you. There was a flower show downtown.
来，这送你的 城里有个花展买的
That's nice of you.
你真贴心
Hey ma, Sue flew in from Baltimore just this morning.
嘿! 妈 苏 今早就要从巴尔地摩搭机了
What do you do, Sue? I sell corporate decorative art.
你从事什么工作? 苏 我是卖一些公司的装饰艺品的
I've met you before. Yeah, you know, she stayed at the motel, ma.
我以前见过你喔? 对啊!妈你该知道他住过我们旅馆
That's how we met.
我们就是那样认识的
And where you're from originally? Uh, I'm from Columbia. Maryland.
那你在哪出生的? 呃..我在马里兰的哥伦比亚区出生
Do you come from a good family? Uhm, no not really.
你家庭正常吗?..(死老太婆) 嗯... 不是很好
Is there something specifically wrong with your family?
你家庭有什么具体的问题吗?
Uh, well my father lives in ashram, in northern California.
呃…我父亲住在加州北边的嬉皮村
Pretty much sums up everything. About, you know...
总之多到每件事都不好 你该想得到...
He once forgot to pick me up from gymnastics. For an entire night.
他曾经在我上完体操课 整晚忘了载我回家
That's quite a lot of somersaults.
那实在可以做好多翻跟斗了
I didn't care. I didn't. It really just explains more about him, um, than it does about me.
我不在乎，真的
Could you hand me those pills, Mike? Which ones?
可以帮我拿些药片吗? 麦克 哪一瓶?
The ones on the left, Mike.
左边那一瓶，麦克
Can I talk to my son in private for a moment? Did I, did I say something wrong?
我可以和我儿子私下说下话吗? 我有..我有说错什么吗?
Not at all. It'll just be a moment.
没什么 只要一会就好
Okay.
好吧
I like her. Really?
我喜欢她 真的?
She's a bit of a long shot. But then she's logical.
她本是毫无机会的 但会那样是合情合理的..
In an emotionally annihilated kind of way.
..处于一种情感上的麻痹
But that's okay, underneath there is a heart of...
但那些都不重要 真情是那个什么做的内心...
Gold? No, I wouldn't say gold.
黄金? 不, 我又没要说“黄金”
Maybe made of leather.
搞不好是...皮革做的
But if it works out, she'll be good for you when I'm gone.
但如果顺利的话 在我走了后她会是你的贤内助
Needless to say what would make me happy is for you to find
在我死前你能找到自己的幸福
something for yourself before my check out time.
对我来说已了无遗憾
Just so I know it's not you and your father alone here, walking around like robots.
这样你和你爸就不会孤独的 像机器人般的行尸走肉过活
Ma, dad's not a robot. He is.
妈! 老爸不是机器人啦! 他就是
But I was mostly talking about you.
但我可几乎都在说你
Unless you find a way out.
除非你能自我突破
Of what? Of whatever it is you're stuck in.
突破什么? 就是你那执着顽固的性格
You get it from your father. He came back from the war stuck.
那来自你爸遗传 他自战争的重担中归来
Been talking about joining the gym ever since.
自那以后就一直说要参加健身房
Never has. But that doesn't have to be you.
光说不练 你不可以变成那样
Are you okay? Yeah, are you?
你没事吧? 没, 你呢?
Yeah.
很好
She liked you. No she doesn't.
她喜欢你 不! 她不喜欢
Yeah, she did, she told me.
有! 她喜欢，她告诉我的
What took you so long?
怎拖那么久?
Dad, you remember Sue?
爸, 记得 苏吗?
There's a toilet overflow in 110.
110有个马桶泛滥了
Okay.
知道了
Gotta get home to your mom.
得回家看你妈了
Are you really leaving? I have to.
你真的要离开了? 我得走
You can't stay one more night? I have meetings this afternoon in Seattle.
你不能多待一个晚上吗? 我傍晚在西雅图有好几个会议
Call them off and just stay for a while.
打电话都推掉啊， 多待一下子嘛!
It's my job. I know.
这是我的工作 我知道啦!
But you know, you could get a job around here. Where, Sechuan house?
但你在这附近也可以找到工作啊 在哪里, 就这栋房子?
No.
不
I'm just saying that... Mike, don't know how to say this...
我是在说... 麦克, 我不知道要怎么说...
This isn't gonna work.
这是行不通的
I mean I'll stop by when I pass through.
我是说当我路过时我会驻足这里
Come on, what do you mean?
好啦, 说清楚一点?
I can't move from Baltimore to live in a corner double room of your parents motel.
我不能搬离巴尔地摩来住 你父母旅馆的角间双人房
I mean...
我是说...
Be serious.
很严肃的...
I'm sorry. I'll stay in better touch this time.
我很抱歉! 我会记住这次更多的感动..
Yeah, whatever you say.
算了，随你怎么说了
So this is where she wanted? This used to be all scrub.
那么这里就是她想要的归所? 这以前都是灌木丛
She'd be cringing right now if she knew they'd be building here.
如果她知道有人要在这里盖房子 她一定马上厌烦起来
But. I promised her I'd do it.
但，对她的承诺我还是会做
Yeah, it's still nice.
是啊! 那还是很窝心的
I meant to give this to you earlier.
早些时候我就想把这给你
It's your mom's favorite piece of jewelry. As you know she was a necklace woman.
这是你妈特别喜爱的一件首饰 你知道她是个爱项链的女人
She thought you should have it. Dunno why since you won't be wearing it,
她认你该拥有它 搞不懂她怎么都不戴了..但..
maybe you'll find some use for it. Someday.
或许你会找到人戴上它.. 总有一天
Thanks, dad. Also I had some guy call me. Wanted to buy the motel.
爸，谢了
You're gonna do it? I doubt it, think we'll just keep running it.
你要那么做?!
But you can do what you like Mike. You know, if you wanna leave...
但你可以去做想做的，麦克 知道吗，如果你想离开的话...
This ain't half bad hunky dory. Yeah, it was my mother's.
这算不错，最高等级的 是啊! 是我妈的
Oh god, it's not going down the sentimental road. Oh, no I'm just saying...
喔!天啊!这里不是多愁善感之地 喔!不是啦! 我只是在说...
Yeah, I know what you're saying and I know you're gonna start crying.
是喔! 我知道你要说什么 而我也知道接下来你要开始哭罗
What? I'm not. How long you've been in the porn business?
啥?我才不会 你搞色情勾当多久啦?
The porn business?
色情勾当?!(色情与典当谐音)
No, pawn business. How long you've been in the pawn business?
不!是典当事业 他妈的典当这行你干多久了?
Oh...no, I'm uh...never...I'm... Exactly.
喔..不! 我..呃..从来没.. 那就是了!
So when someone says he ain't gonna start crying
每次有人呛说不会哭，
that's sure as shit sign that they are just about to start blubbering like a calf.
到他妈的签字时就像小牛般的‘靠北靠木’
See what I mean? Just, how much, for the necklace?
知道我在说什么吗? 废话少说， 那条项链值多少!?
I'll give you 300. Phh, okay.
我出300! 呼! 好啊!
Oh... Hi. Hi.
喔!...嗨! 嗨!
I'm here to see Sue, please. Sue no longer works here.
我来找 苏，拜托罗! 苏 已经不再来这里工作罗
I'm sorry? She moved to Washington.
不好意思?! 她搬去华盛顿了
D.C.? State.
D.C.(华盛顿特区)? 华盛顿州...
Her old boyfriend came to convince her to move to Aberdeen.
她前男友来这里说服她 搬去亚伯丁
Showed up with flowers, first class plane tickets, it was very 'officer and gentleman'.
一开始就用鲜花博得入门票 简直就像‘军官与绅士’
Uh, number eight.
呃..点8号!
Eight?
8!?
You're new in town right? Oh. Yeah.
你刚到这个城吧? 喔! 是啊
You looking for a job? Yeah.
你在找工作? 嗯
You wanna work here? Seriously?
要不要在这里做? 说真的捏?
Why the fuck wouldn't I be serious?
我他妈的怎会不是认真的?
Al. Mike.
艾尔 麦克
Mike, it is nice to meet you man. Yeah, you too.
麦克老兄, 高兴与你认识 是啊, 也高兴认识你
Dude, you stink. I do?
老兄, 你身上很臭 是喔?
Big time. You can't work here if you stink.
超级臭! 如果你有恶臭就不能在这里工作
It's my parents place, they're old school and they really hate stinky people.
这是我父母的店，他们守旧 而且痛恨发臭的人
OK
好
So okay, go home, take a shower, please, come back and I will get you the job.
那么拜托回家洗个澡 然后过来我就给你这份工作
I don't really have a home. Really?
我没有真正家耶 是喔?
All right, he also needs a place to live so I was thinking that
好吧!他也需要住的地方， 我想我们可以让他住地下室
maybe we could you know let him stay in the basement  and deduct some rent from his pay?
然后从薪水扣掉一些当租金
Great.
很好啊...
Hey thanks for helping me out, it really means a lot.
嘿! 真的多谢助我脱离困境 我是说真的非常感谢!
Dude, no problem, man.
没什么啦! 兄弟
You know I've been trying to get my folks sign someone American anyway
知道吗? 我想尽办法要我父母雇用美国人
cause we can't less bigger bullshit that way.
那样的话我们就可以好好臭屁一下
Plus I freaking hate working the mornings. Why?
加上我超级讨厌在这时间工作 怎么说?
Because I like smoking pot and sleeping in.
我抽很多大麻会想睡觉啦
Oh that's cool. So why did you come to Aberdeen, Mike?
那很酷喔 那么你为何要来亚伯丁? 麦克
Uh, this girl that I'm in love with, she moved here to be with her ex boyfriend.
呃..我爱上了这个女人 她跟他的艺人朋友搬来这里
Oh, that sucks, man. Yeah.
喔!..逊毙了，兄弟 对啊
Yeah, especially considering the guy is a punk.
是啊! 特别是这家伙搞不好是个流氓
Like a punk punk? Ex punk, think he's older now.
像那些庞克混混? 呃..庞克艺人，现在应该老了
Does he train dogs? I dunno.
他有养狗吗? 我不知道
Is his name like Jango? Yeah, I think it is!
他是不是叫 强哥? 对! 我想是就是他!
I have totally heard of this dude, Mike.
这老兄我太熟了，麦克
Is he a punk? No, he's an ex punk!
他是个流氓?! 不! 他是个庞克艺人!
So the thing with this guy right, he's also a yoghurt magnate.
之前说的没错，这家伙是庞克 也是个奶酪老板
Ok, totally huge in a yoghurt business, this guy is like a yoghurt fucking mogul.
对了!在庞大的奶酪业界 这家伙他妈的就是个奶酪大亨
You see those kennels over there? That's where he keeps the dogs.
看到那堆狗舍没有? 那就是他养狗的地方
Damn it! What?
该死! 怎?
This guy, this guy is like a total stud. What do you mean?
这家伙，这家伙简直就是个种马 那是什么意思?
I'm not a sexual superman. This guy...
我不是个打炮超人 而这家伙...
I mean...
我是说...
No dude, you're probably fine. You're just saying that.
不!老兄，你应该也很能“干”的 你就只会那么说而已
Yeah, that's true but what do you want me to say, that you're right? No, but...
是!你希望我那么说也是事实 对吧!? 没啦，但...
Ok, look. Now, chicks these days, they don't want sexual supermen,
好!现在听着! 近年来的小妞 她们不喜欢打炮超人
ok they want hard workers. You know, guys who hustle.
对!她们要的是卖力做的人 知道吗? 苦干实“干”的人
I mean you're a fucking hustler Mike.
我说你是“苦干实干”的家伙 麦克
I mean you came all the way out to Aberdeen dude, that's gotta count for something right? Yeah.
我说你大老远跑来亚伯丁 不就是为了一些事吗? 对吧!?
Dude I think I got an idea for how you're gonna get your girl back.
兄弟，我想我有个点子 好让你抢回马子
Really? See that dude sitting over there?
真的? 坐在那边的老兄看到没?
He runs a flight school over in Olympia.
他在奥林匹亚开间飞行学校
You should talk to him Mike.
你该跟他聊一下，麦克
Ok Mike, what I need now is for you to free your mind!
好了麦克! 现在我需要的 就是你要放松心情!
So let us have a spiritually fulfilling religious fucking moment!
那么我们就来个他妈的 虔诚心灵的爽快时刻!
I'm pretty sure I can do it Stan!
我超级肯定做不到啊! 史丹!
That's the Michael I've come to know in the past eight hours!
你是我过去认识8小时的麦克!
That's the Mike!
你就是麦克!
Come on now!
现在来吧!
Three, two, one... Wait! Wait, Stan!
3..2..1..! 等下! 等等, 史丹!
Okay now Mike, you're on your ooooooown!
好罗! 麦克 现在... 该你自己.....罗!!!!
Jesus! God! Jangoooo!
天啊! 强哥! 强哥!
Oh my god! Who is, who is that?
喔!我的天! 是谁? 那是谁啊!?
It's me, Mike.
是我啦! 麦克!
Mike?
麦克?
What are you doing? Mike, come here.
你在搞啥飞机? 麦克, 快上来!
Jango, cut up with shooting!
强哥! 停下你的射击!
What the fuck is going on!
这是他妈的怎回事!
Jango, stop shooting people! Stop it!
强哥! 别再射人啦! 停下来!!
Come here, follow my hand.
到这来, 顺着我的手
Stop it!
停下来!!!
Here, I got you.
来, 抓好了
Oh god, are you okay?
喔! 天啊! 你没事吧?!
Stay away. Sue.
闪开点...苏
Jango, give me the gun, give me the damn gun. I'm gonna die.
强哥，枪给我，把该死的枪给我 我快死了...
It's just a bb gun. No, I really think I'm dying.
只是个BB枪而已 不! 我真觉得快死了
Oh my god! Get back, Sue. Come here.
喔! 我的天! 后退, 苏 看我的!
Jango, what are you doing? CPR!
强哥! 你在做什么?! C.P.R!
Oh my god I'm calling an ambulance.
天啊! 我要叫救护车了!
Well that just looks like you're kissing him, Jango.
那看起来就像你在跟他亲嘴耶! 强哥!
Where am I? The Aberdeen medical center.
我在哪里? 亚伯丁中央医院
Did uh, did... Yeah, Jango shot you.
我被..呃..被... 对! 强哥用枪射你
Which caused you to go into shock.
是你引起骚动的
Mike, why? Why did you come out here?
为何这样? 麦克 为何你跑来这里?
Because I love you.
因为我爱你啊
That...Do I have bb hose in my neck? Yeah.
那个...我脖子上有BB弹孔吗? 有啊!
That hurt. Well I can imagine.
痛死了! 想也知道
I thought it was over with that guy?
我想那家伙做得太过分了
It's good for me, Mike.
那是为我好，麦克
He put me in charge of his company's non profit yoghurt fund
他让我掌管他的慈善优格基金会，让我为很多人做很多好事
He also feels horrible for shooting you and he would like to have you over for dinner.
同时对于射伤你觉的不厚道 所以想请你吃顿晚餐
Oooh, that's nice.
喔...!不错哟
Hey, so who's this guy?
嘿! 这家伙是谁?
That is me and Joe Strummer in the summer of '79 at the 100 Club in London.
那是我和 乔 史特拉莫79年夏天 在伦敦100俱乐部照的
Who is Joe Strummer?
乔 史特拉莫 是谁啊?
Joe Strummer most likely made love to your mother Al and wrote a song about it.
艾尔，乔 史特拉莫 似乎是 和你老妈做爱后写了那首歌的
Here's the two of us throwing over at the CBGB's.
这是我们两个在CBGB乡村酒吧 ‘抓兔子’照的
Hey, who is that?
嘿! 那个是谁?
Ah, that's me and Ed McMahon. Ed Mc Wild Mahon.
那是我和 艾德 麦克马洪.. 狂野的 艾德 麦克马洪
Now he's a true punker.
他是个货真价实的庞克乐手
Basically for me, dog work is a thrill, adrenaline rush if you will,
如果你要那样说的话，基本上
that's otherwise hard for me to replicate in the world of yoghurt.
养狗让我兴奋，肾上腺素激增
Especially now that you're not a punk.
特别是你现在已不是个庞克乐手了
Well I'll always be a punker in here, Al. Make no mistake.
我一直都是个庞克乐手，艾尔 别搞错了
But there's less need for me to call myself a punker
但当这非常重视理念的庞克世界被广大市场商业化后
in a world where very notion of punk then means commodified for the mass market. OK.
也没必要称呼我自己是庞克乐手了 好吧!
How do you like your masala? It's really good.
马萨拉菜还喜欢吧? 很好吃耶!
Oh, you're not gonna eat any? Oh, I liquified it.
喔!你怎么都不吃点东西? 不!我把菜榨成汁来喝
Listen, I would just like to formally and quite sincerely apologize to you for the BB gun incident.
听着，我想要正式及真诚的为BB枪事情向你道歉
I lost my cool.
我太不冷静了
I was scared, for Sue. Scared for the dogs. Scared for the general well being of the pool.
我很害怕，为了 苏，为了狗 为了游泳池整体安宁而害怕
So I just wanna say that I'm sorry, m m... Mike... my friend.
我只想说对不起..嗯..嗯 麦克...
I blundered. Yeah, it's alright.
我的朋友...我错了 嗯! 没事了
Yeah so that's, behind us!
是啊! 那些不愉快就.. 丢到屁股后面罗!
And Sue tells me that you're a painter?
另外 苏跟我说你是个画家?
Yeah, very, very talented painter.
是啊! 非常非常有才的画家
When did you have the opportunity to become acquainted with the quality of his work, Sue?
何时你有这个机会 对他的画作品质这么熟悉? 苏
That was my last business trip for uh, Corporate Bliss.
那是我在 比利斯集团 最后的一次业务旅行
And you thought, uh "a great opportunity to promote my art" or you thought "beautiful woman"?
而你想的是“推销作品的好机会” 还是想着“有美女”?
First part. The um art one.
前面那部份..嗯.. 作品那个
Now so you're the guy who paints foxes and and hounds for corporate art?
那么现在你就是帮那公司 做狐狸和猎犬画作的家伙?
Okay, cause I got something to say about that.
是啊! 好啊! 正好我对那个有话要说
You take a, a Rottweiler, no, let's say a Malinois...
你画了一..一只 罗威那犬 不! 我们把它叫 玛利诺犬好了..
chasing a fox, see you've got a seriously new dynamic on your hands
在追一只狐狸.. 那么新颖生动的景象出自你手..
because a Malinois on a fox's ass, that would be a trip.
因为一只玛利诺 摸着狐狸屁股 那应该是个笔误
because a Malinois is gonna turn that little fox into a fox meat inside a twenty three seconds,
因为玛利诺要在23秒内把小狐狸扒光变成狐狸肉，你清楚我说的
So I've decided a lobby for that little bit. Okay.
所以我决定大厅要弄点那样的画 好啊
That was really great chicken, Jango. I loved that fucking chicken Jango.
这鸡肉实在好吃，强哥 我爱死这他妈的鸡了，强哥
You'd have a better chicken in there, you'd have to be a rooster.
你们想要吃到更好的鸡 得要自己变成公鸡喔
Speaking up, who's up for some dessert?
我大声的说，谁想来个甜点? 好啊!
I got a new flavour I wanna try on you guys: Henry Rollins' chicken wing crunch.
我有个新菜色想让你们试试.. 亨利 罗林斯的‘碎碎鸡翅’
Hey Sue, Mike and I are gonna go to the Cowboy Club after this and if you want to join us?
嘿苏! 麦克和我饭后要去牛仔吧 你要不要去?
You know they've got really great dancing.
你知道那边的舞实在很棒
I'll think about it.
我考虑一下
What I'm trying to say is that China is not only gonna kick America's economic butt
我说的不只是中国打垮美国经济 而且还会侵袭整个美国
but it's gonna invade the whole country.
你们会换掉新国旗还一些有的没的 我没被侵袭...
You need to reorient your way you think about Asians,
你们得适应对亚洲人的看法
because we will blow your mind with our uniqueness and inner beauty.
因为我们会用我们的独特性 和内在美让你们大吃一惊
You think she's hot?
你觉得她火辣吗?
Yeah, sort of.
嗯..有那么一点
Hi, guys. Sue. Hi.
嗨! 大伙儿 苏! 嗨..
Hi, Mike.
嗨! 麦克
You didn't bring Jango, did you?
你没带强哥过来，对吧?
No, no he's got kinda drunk so, I've just told him that I had an errand.
没，没! 他喝醉了 我只告诉他我有些事要做
Hey, you wanna dance with us, Sue? No.
嘿! 要不要一起跳舞? 苏 不要!
Come on, I know you got a move. I don't have a move.
少来了!我知道你有舞步 我没有舞步
Everybody's got a move, Sue. Mike, show her your move.
每个人都嘛会一两招，苏 麦克! 秀你的招给她看
I don't have a move. Sue, don't you think Mike's got moves?
我没舞招 苏! 你认为麦克不会跳舞吗?
I bet you have, a move.
我赌你有..舞步
Come on, let's pass some moves.
来喔! 我们来飙舞罗!
Hey, did you hear? Aberdeen is building the biggest bio diesel field plant in the country.
嘿! 你知道吗? 亚伯丁正在兴建 国内最大的生化柴油发电厂
Whatever you say man.
随便你怎么掰，兄弟
No, we should find a way to get in on that.
不!我们应该找个管道去插一脚啊
Hey, Jango.
嘿! 强哥
You know why I'll always be a punker man?
你知道为何我一直是个庞克人吗? 为何?
Cause I take very little shit.
麦克 因为我有点坏坏的
I'm watching you man. You stay away from her.
我会看好你的，老兄! 离她远一点
Mike, Mike, you all right?
麦克! 麦克! 没事吧?
I'll get him back. Yeah man, that is a piece of scum, man.
我会讨回来的 对阿!只是一块人渣, 兄弟
I think he'll regret that.
他缓筢悔那样做的...
So you're sure you wanna do this? Look, don't come if you don't want.
那么你确定要这么做? 听好! 没种就不要来!
Dude.
兄弟!
I'm with you.
我挺你!
Okay, let's do it.
好! 我们干吧!
Dude, that was awesome!
兄弟! 太棒了!
Just...
可以了...
Wait, wait. Drop. Go go go go!
等，等一下! 丢掉啦! 闪..闪..闪人!
Hold on. Shit!
抓好啦! 干!
I love you, Sue!
我爱你! 苏!
Hear that old man! You suck.
听好了! 老头子! 你逊毙了!
Mike, you have visitor. Okay.
麦克，有人找你 知道啦...
We need to talk, Mike. I know.
我们得谈一下 我知道
I've been leaving you messages.
我一直留言给你
Did you tell him about us? Yes.
你跟他说过我们的事? 说了
Why?
为什么?
Because I'm marrying him.
因为我跟他就要结婚了
What?
啥?
Which I need you to accept.
这件事我需要你的认可
Why?
为何?
Because I'm at a point in my life where there are certain things that I need.
因为我有了生命中一些 必然需要的事物
Like what?
比如什么?
Like a certain kind of love.
像是一种爱情
What kind?
哪一种?
The kind that is not like an unguided missile.
这不是那种漫无目的乱来的爱
You can't just stalk people around the country.
你不可以在国内到处跟踪人
You can't parachute into people's pools.
你不能随便跳伞到人家水池里
Knock on people's motel rooms just because you're feeling lonely.
不能只因为你觉得寂寞 就去敲旅馆客人的房门
Life isn't like that.
人生不是那样过的
Freedom to be with someone. It's not all about what you need.
自由人人都有 但不是你那样的随心所欲
It's got to be more selfless than that. Mike, it's got to be more selfless than that.
那种无私超越了你所谓的爱，麦克 那无私已超过爱了!
Oh, like, like save everyone else in the world except yourself?
喔! 像是，像是拯救世上所有人 而弃自己不顾?
I don't, that's not what I do. Yes you do.
我不是，我没那样子 你就是那样子
No. It's not. Yes it is!
不..没那回事 对! 是那回事!
You're so busy being selfless that you end up treating yourself like shit.
你就这么忙碌于无私 最后却像废物般对待自己
That really what you think of me?
那就是你对我真正的看法?
I'm just, I'm just saying...I know what you need.
我只是，我只是说... 我知道你需要什么
Which is what? To take care of yourself a little.
那个需要是什么? 稍微关心一下你自己
So that the people who love you don't feel like they're annoying you.
那么爱你的人才不会觉得 爱你等于在惹恼你
Sue, Sue, just, marry me.
苏! 苏..就..嫁给我!
Hey, let's just let the world go screw itself for a half second.
嘿! 就让这世界自己运转一下下
And just see what happens and maybe it'll be okay.
看看会发生什么 或许会没事也说不定
I'm getting married on Saturday. Why?
我准备星期六结婚 为何?
Cause I'm pregnant.
因为我怀孕了
And I'm gonna have it. It's what I want.
我要生下来，这是我想要的
You're having a child?
你有了小孩?
Could it be mine?
有..有可能是我的吗?
No.
不是
Which is why I'm getting married.
那是我要结婚的原因
Mike I can't afford to be selfish on this one.
麦克，对于这件事我无法承担自私
I just have to be with somebody who knows what they're doing with their life.
我只能与有人生方向的人在一起
I'm sorry.
很对不起
Sweet just doesn't cut it.
温柔还是无法切断它的(婚礼)
Can you leave now, please?
你现在可以走了吗? 拜托..
Just leave, okay.
离开就对了, 好吗?
Get out of my basement, Sue.
离开我的地下室，苏..
Susan, I'm serious. Get the fuck out of my basement right now!
苏, 我严正声明 他妈的马上滚离我的地下室!
I wish I had that dick's bb gun right now.
真希望现在有把那个废人的BB枪
They're going on a honeymoon? I don't know.
他们会去度蜜月吗? 我不知道
Yeah, they'll probably wait till the yoghurt season's over.
对!他们大概会等奶酪期结束再去
You're gonna be all right. Yeah.
你会好好过活的 是啊!
I just wanna say Al, you're the best friend I ever had.
我只想说，艾尔 你是我这辈子最好的朋友
Ditto.
你也一样是
What a douchebag huh?
让人很不爽，嗄?
You know that's enough to make you want to be a buddhist monk.
你知道那就足够让你会去出家当和尚了
My people are really good at that stuff.
我们中国人很会搞那一套
Yeah?
是吗?
Oh dude, don't get carried away.
喔!兄弟，不要想太多...
Michael, the progress you've made in your 4 months here has been remarkable.
麦克，这4个月来你进步非凡
Thank you, father.
谢谢师父
Needless to say your immersion in the duty of carriage shopper
你待人之道与领袖特质的专注修行
and boon chief has been full and complete. Thank you.
都已圆满，自不待言 谢谢夸奖
But some worries have arisen. Such as what, father?
不过一些隐忧也浮现出来了 比如说呢? 师父
First of all you're not supposed to call me father.
首先，你不应该叫我师父
But I must say, I must admit I grow fond of it.
但我必须说 我是由衷欢喜的
Michael...
麦克...
An aspiring buddhist monk such as yourself should seek to produce a heart that does not dwell.
像你这般一心向佛的和尚 应该寻求、引导内心无牵挂
Of course, father.
当然的,师父
And your heart Michael, may I say, does dwell.
然而你的心，麦克 容我说下..有挂碍
No it doesn't. It does, Michael.
不! 没有 有的, 麦克
You have not transcended your earthly passions.
你还没超脱你以往的激情
To put it bluntly: you are stuck!
开门见山的说: 你无法自拔!
You also spend too much time playing volleybal.
你也花太多时间在玩排球
Yeah but I thought that was permitted father.
对! 但我以为那是被允许的， 师父
Yes but not for seven hours a day. Also you encouraged it for stress release.
没错! 但不是一打就是7小时 你也鼓励以它来舒缓紧张情绪
Yes, I, I did. Yes. But uh, Michael,
是!我是这么做，但是麦克佛教僧是无须用一天7小时来释压的
We are buddhist monks. Buddhist monks.
我们是佛教僧.. 佛教的和尚
So what should I do?
那么我该怎么做?
My parents died when I was ten.
我十岁父母双亡
Two months later my uncle and I moved to America.
两月后叔父与我搬来美国
I was forced to let go of everything I knew. In order to move on.
为了要继续往前走 我不得已要将所有过去抛弃
Sometimes in life, you must do that.
人生在世.. 有时你得那么做
Where are you from, father?
你哪里出生的? 师父
Vietnam. Hau Liang province?
越南，河内省
My parents were killed in a war.
我双亲死于战争
By the Americans? Yes.
被美国人..? 是的
And yet I moved here.
然而我搬到这里
I like this park.
我喜欢这里的公园
I'm sorry. No no no.
我很抱歉 不..不..不
It is not your fault.
那不是你的错
Let go, Michael. Let go and move on.
让它去，麦克 让他随风而逝并向前进
I reckon I knew you. Yeah, I'm the guy who sold you my mom's necklace.
我认为我认识你喔 对!我就是那个出卖母亲项链的家伙
Oh yes, right.
喔! 没错!
What can I do you for? I want it back.
需要什么服务? 我要赎回来
Dad, do you want me to make you some dinner? No, I'm all right.
爸，要不要我帮你做些晚饭? 不用, 我还不饿
Dad, when you were over in Vietnam, did you ever do any fighting in the Hau Liang province?
爸，你在越南那时候 有没在河内打过仗?
Yeah. Why?
有啊! 干嘛问?
I just met this guy at the monastery who was from the area.
我正好认识个庙里的人 是从那地区过来的
Seemed to really have his shit together.
似乎跟他的不堪往事很吻合
Good to hear.
听起来不错
Dad, I been thinking, maybe you should sell this place.
爸，我在想 或许你该把这里卖掉
You don't even like it here.
你根本不喜欢这里一切
This was mom's thing.
这是妈的活儿
Why do you say that?
你何以那么说?
Cause it's true.
因为那是事实
My mom loved people, loved running things, it's not like you.
妈喜欢人们，喜欢做事情 不像你..
You're not like a people's person, dad.
你是个不擅于跟人打交道的人 老爸
You should let it go.
你该放手了
Move on.
往前走过自己的人生
Otherwise you're just gonna rot.
否则你会慢慢腐败退化
Sell it and do what? Anything.
卖了后要做啥事? 任何事都可以
You've still got time. You've got money.
你依然有时间，而且有钱
What do you need Mike? A loan.
那你需要什么? 麦克 还贷款?
No. I just wanted to say, that this doesn't have to be it.
不! 我只是想说... 没必要过得如此
And that I love you.
还有 我爱你
Dear Mike, I know you probably don't want to hear from me and I can't say I blame you.
亲爱的麦克，我知道或许你不想 听到我声音，我不能怪你
But I wanted to write anyway to let you know what I think.
但无论如何我要让你知道 我的想法..
Which is that I think you had a point that day.
就是那天你提到的
About people who hide behind their causes.
关于人们为了避免生活的冲突
in order to avoid their lives
以致躲在真实自己的背后
You had a point down there in that basement. With the soy sauce and the mice.
你在那全是酱油和老鼠的地下室 说的很对
And so I wanted to say thanks.
为此我要向你道谢
Because of you Mike, I'm not the same person I was.
因为你，麦克 我不再是从前的我
Goodbye, Mike. Love, Sue.
再见了，麦克 爱你的 苏
Just thought about what you said the other day.
想想那天你说的话
I think you had a point.
我认为你说的很有道理
That being said, this is yours.
也就是说，这是你的了
What is it? Deed to the motel. Signed over to you.
这是什么? 旅馆地契，寄在你名下了
Dad. Dad, that's not why.... It's fine.
爸，爸，那不是为何.. 这样很好
I don't need it.
我不需要了
Your mom was good about that. You can't just give me the motel.
你妈把这里打里得很好 你不可以就这样把旅馆给我啊!
It's your birth right.
今天你生日对吧?!
What would you do?
那你打算要做什么?
I want to get in shape.
我要做的还捉摸不定
Maybe join one of those basketball leagues.
或许去参加那些篮球社团
How about you? I don't know. I'll think of something.
那你呢? 我不知道，我还得思考一下
You done with the monk stuff? Yeah, I still ocassionally do it.
和尚那些修行你都做完了? 对啊! 我偶尔还是会做一下
I mean not professionally but...
我是说不是很熟练但...
What about that girl?
那个女孩勒?
Oh, that didn't work out.
喔! 进展没成功
We weren't, you know, like, meant for each other.
我们没在一起，你知道的 像是..各自纷飞
I dunno Mike, things change. In life.
我听不懂，麦克 生命中任何事都会改变的
What do you mean?
你言下之意..?
You're not the same guy you were.
你不再是以前那个二愣子了
Good soup.
汤好喝
You can do this, Mike.
你做得来的，麦克
I'm gonna hit the gym.
我要去体育馆动一下
Yeah, they have a senior citizens hoop run from 3 to 5.
是吗!? 3点到5点有个长青组篮赛
I got a new ball.
我买了个新球
Yeah, I see it.
有啊! 看到了
All right, Mike. See ya.
就这样罗! 麦克 再见
Hallo? Hi Jango, it's Mike, Sue's friend.
哈罗? 嗨! 强哥，我是麦克，苏的朋友
Hi Mike.
嗨! 麦克
Hi. Look I know that I'm probably not the guy you want to hear from right now
嗨听着!我知道或许你现在不想 听到我这家伙的声音
but I need to tell Sue about what I'm doing down here.
但是我得告诉 苏 我在这边做的事
And I think that when she hears what I'm up to... Hey Mike?
我想当她听到我想去做... 嘿!麦克?
...she will at least understand that if nothing else...
...至少要让她知道 不然的话...
Mike? Yeah?
麦克? 是!?
We split up, Sue and I. Split up. She left me.
我们离婚了，苏 和我离婚了 苏 离开我..
Went back to Maryland to be with her mom.
..回去马里兰和她妈一起住了
Hi Hi.
嗨! 嗨!
Are you Mary Claussen? Yes?
您是 玛莉 克劳森 吗? 是的?!
I'm a friend of Sue's. Is she home?
我是 苏的朋友 她在家吗?
Who are you? Mike? From management.
你是谁 麦克，经营旅馆的
Sue, Mike is here.
苏，麦克来了
How's the baby?
宝宝好吗?
So far so good.
到目前都很好
Are you okay?
你过的好吗?
I'm really sorry, Mike.
我实在很抱歉，麦克
For what?
怎么说?
Cause I really messed up. With you.
因为我实在很刻薄..对待你
But you were right. I was like a kid.
但你没错啊 过去我太天真
This is the deed to the motel.
这是旅馆的地契
I want to turn it into a homeless shelter with midnight basketball.
我要把它改建成可打午夜篮球 的游民之家
I already bought the soup noodles.
汤面摊子我买好了 (他们唱歌时那一台就是面摊子)
I was actually hoping that you might want to help.
我很切确希望你愿意来帮忙
I really love you Sue and I want to take care of you and whoever it is that's inside of you.
我实在很爱你 苏
All I want is to be with you. That's it.
所有我想要的就是与你厮守 就这么简单
Breathe, Sue.
调节呼吸，苏
Just keep breathing.
保持呼吸均匀就好喔
I wrote you a haiku, you wanna hear it?
我为你写了一首俳句诗 想听吗?
Sure.
当然要!
Mike, oh Mike, my man. Keeps showing up like UPS.
麦克，喔!麦克，我的男人 老像个不断电的UPS跑出来
Sue, you're such a bitch.
苏，你实在是个十足的滥货
I like it.
我喜欢!
You do? Yeah.
你真的喜欢? 是啊!